<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY version "1.4">
]>

<article id="index" lang="en"> <!-- please do not change the id-->

  <articleinfo> 
    <title>WFYD Manual</title>
    <copyright>
      <year>2005</year>
      <holder>Chris McDonough</holder>
    </copyright>

    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">

      <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify
      this document under the terms of the <ulink type="help"
      url="ghelp:fdl"><citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
      License</citetitle></ulink>, Version 1.1 or any later version
      published by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant
      Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.  A copy
      of the license can be found <ulink type="help"
      url="ghelp:fdl">here</ulink>.
      </para>

      <para>Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their
      products and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those
      names appear in any GNOME documentation, and those trademarks
      are made aware to the members of the GNOME Documentation
      Project, the names have been printed in caps or initial caps.
      </para>

    </legalnotice>

    <releaseinfo> 
         This is version 0.1 of the WFYD manual.
     </releaseinfo> 
<!-- this is version of manual, not application --> 
  </articleinfo>

<!-- =============Document Body ============================= -->



<!-- =============Introduction ============================= -->
  <sect1 id="introduction">
      <title>Introduction</title> 
    <sect2 id="whatis">
    <title>What is WFYD?</title>
    <para>
      <application>WFYD</application> 
      is a simple application that may be used to keep track of time
      spent on projects.  It is meant to be as simple and feature-free
      as possible.
    </para>
    <para>
     Features include:
     <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
    <emphasis>Creating Projects</emphasis>
          Projects are names.  A project contains one or more "entries".
          </para> 
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
    <emphasis>Creating Entries</emphasis>

           Entries are line items associated with a project.  An entry
           consists of a start time, an amount of time spent, and a
           series of notes describing what happened during this
           period.

          </para> 
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
    <emphasis>Nag</emphasis>
        WFYD can be configured to nag you on a scheduled basis to make
        a new entry or stop the current entry timer.
          </para> 
        </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>


<sect1 id="usage"> 
   <title>Using WFYD</title>
   <sect2 id="working">
      <title>Working with WFYD</title>

<para>
        When you first start <application>WFYD</application>, you see
        the <interface>Main window</interface>, as shown in 
  <xref linkend="mainwindowfig"/>.
<!-- ==============Figure=================================== -->
        <figure id="mainwindowfig" xreflabel="WFYD Main Window">
          <title>WFYD Main Window</title>
          <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>WFYD main window, with no projects created</screeninfo>
      <graphic fileref="figures/wfyd-main.png" />
          </screenshot>
        </figure>
<!-- ==============End of Figure=================================== -->
</para>      


      <para>
      The main window consists of five areas. There is a menu bar at
      the top of the window, a project list and a set of buttons below
      the menu bar, a notes entry window, and an entry list for the
      currently selected project.  There is also a status bar at the
      bottom of the window.
</para>

<para>

      When you start <application>WFYD</application> for the first
      time, the project list, the notes entry window, and the entry
      list will be empty.
</para>

<para>      You cannot add an entry unless a project is selected.

      Add a new project by typing its name into the project list entry box.
</para>
<para>


      To start an entry that will be applied to the currently selected
      project, click the <guibutton>Add</guibutton> button near the top
      left of the main window.  When you do so, the button will display
      the current time spent on this entry in minutes.  Clicking the button
      again will stop the timer and add the entry to the entry list for
      the currently selected project.
</para>

<para>
      Notes typed into the notes field will be entered into the entry
      when the entry has been completed.

      You can also start a new entry by typing into the notes box.

      You can end an entry by pressing ctrl-G instead of clicking on the <guibutton>Add</guibutton> button.
</para>

<para>
      The data related to this program is kept in a file in
      <filename>~/.wfyd.dat</filename>.

   </para>

</sect2>

</sect1>

<!-- =============Authors Section============================= -->

  <sect1 id="authors">
    <title>Authors</title>
    <para>
       <application>WFYD</application> was written by Chris McDonough.
    </para>
    <para>
      Please submit all comments, suggestions, and bug reports 
      on the  
      <ulink url="http://www.plope.com/software/wfyd/">Project site</ulink>
    </para>
</sect1>


</article>















